[Music]
when Nvidia launches a new GPU for
laptops they normally come up with their
best stuff first the most expensive
stuff it's like the latest and greatest
and they try to convince people to buy
the whatever's newest right and then a
few months later they will come out with
that kind of the mid-tier offerings of
that generation and right now in spring
of 2019 we've seen invidious hand so we
have a lot of options to choose from we
have the older generation 10 series
stuff we have their 20 series r-tx like
the prime like best of the best and then
we have their newest 1650 and 1660
gaming laptops now if you're loaded and
you have tons of money to burn then you
pick up a three or four thousand dollar
RTX laptop and you're good to go but for
most people you got to make a decision
as to which one to get so this video is
to kind of help you choose which one of
these would probably the best fit and I
have a particular kind of combination I
think is the best value for your money
right now so I made a video a few months
ago about how r-tx laptops were not a
wise choice to make and months later
we're still in the same position I still
don't recommend most people buying an RT
X gaming laptop because for one they're
super expensive too the technology
hasn't matured like it's been eight
months since r-tx has come out like the
technology was introduced publicly and
there's like three or four playable
games that support our checks there's
battlefield 5 which we've seen a lot of
and there's Tomb Raider and I think
there's a racing game point being it's
not a technology that's being quickly
adopted by developers and I don't blame
them like if your game developer you
have to assign resources to support
ray-traced graphics right it's gonna
take from other projects and stuff like
that it's gonna cost money and you don't
be a company that's backing the wrong
horse you'd want to be the guy that's
like hey we have a ray traced game but
the game isn't very good no one wants to
be that developer so my position still
stands when it comes to RTX laptops most
people should not be buying them still
when it comes to the 10 series devices
these are still good however the well is
drying up the stock levels for the good
GTX 10 series laptops is definitely
dropping so if you want to get one I'll
link some below as to devices that I
still think are quite good for the money
it's just that if you're going to do it
you probably want to do it sooner than
later
and lastly the new ones the 1650 and
1660 devices from Nvidia these GPS are
aimed at the entry to mid to your market
so the devices are a little bit cheaper
but the one of interest to me is the
1660 ti that performance is quite
similar to the 1070 max-q
and because of the newer architecture
it's slightly more energy efficient as
just a better chip overall but there is
one unique device made by Asus which is
running an AMD CPU and that 1660 Ti and
it goes for $1,100 it's the Zephyrus G
I'm gonna be doing a review on that
pretty soon but because it's running an
AMD CPU it's quite a bit cheaper than
devices that are based on Intel stuff um
okay here's the thing right now I'm
using as my daily driver I really hate
that word but the device I use most
frequently is the razor blade from 2017
I'm still running a 1070 max-q even
though I have access to a lot of laptops
I'm someone that recognizes the value of
just using stuff that's really good from
the past and I think this is the message
I want to convey to my audience right
now this year both the companies Nvidia
and Intel are trying to push stuff on to
consumers they're trying to sell us
stuff that we don't need right the stuff
from 2018 was awesome superfast screens
six core CPUs 10 series GPUs this was
seriously like the Golden Age of gaming
laptops and the new stuff is better but
keep in mind what games you're gonna
play what games you'd like to play and
then make a decision based on that
because you can get some really good
stuff still in the 10 series laptops and
if you're gonna buy one of the new ones
I'd lean more towards the 1650 and 1660
devices because as cool as r-tx
technology is the games just aren't
there yet and I know some people are
like you know I want to get a
future-proof laptop by the time RTX is
super popular like get it then get your
gaming device then because by that point
in time the 20 series laptops are gonna
be pretty old okay hope you guys enjoyed
this video thumbs we liked it subs if
you loved it
see you guys next time
[Music]