I've only recently switched over to the
galaxy s 10 II as my primary Android
phone it's still a very fresh phone to
me but last week the P 30 and the P 30
Pro came out from hallway and I thought
I'd give them a run now just right off
the bat I have a strong preference for
the P 30 over the P 30 Pro there's just
a bunch of reasons I'll go through the
big one for me is size obviously if
you've seen my channel I like smaller
phones but it's also like the flat
screen I have mentioned before in the
past how it's Samsung's curved edges on
their phones it's not something that I
find particularly useful very beautiful
to look at but they're just like urgh
anomaly strange to me and the curve on
the the p30 pro it's even more
pronounced it's just not a comfortable
phone for me so I like the flat screen
of the p30 more than the pro and finally
it's the headphone jack I'm someone that
still values the analogue headphone jack
I feel like a lot of people don't care
about it at this point but I just have a
lot of regular headphones that I use and
I like the headphone jack okay camera
wise these are both fantastic cameras
for the people that are interested in
the 50 times zoom on the p30 Pro it's a
cool feature but it borders on gimmicky
like there's just so little real world
use for it I feel like for most people I
know for myself
I would never use that thing I would set
up like the first couple of days to see
how cool it is it's just it's cool but
it's you know you know what I'm talking
about alright
p30 however has a fantastic camera they
both have fantastic cameras but the
night mode it's unbelievable it's
essentially night vision like it'll
capture usable images when it looks
completely dark to my eye it takes a few
seconds to capture the image like any
phone doing a dedicated night shot but
it's honestly impressive and it produces
better results than the competitors the
regular low-light photos so that's just
like auto mode in lower light but not
pitch-black those are also very good but
I don't think it stands out as far ahead
from the competition if anything I'd say
that the pixel 3 has slightly cleaner
photos when you're just doing auto mode
but the p30 phones have excellent
cameras all around one thing I did
notice in terms of the camera it's not
where's camera for stills but for video
and you'll see it in other videos where
the image looks a little pink like
particular skin tones they just look
very red or pink and I just have like a
theory on that these phones were made by
qua way a Chinese company and I think
the majority of the people buying these
phones are gonna be from China and
there's a thing about skin tone like so
I'm Asian I have Asian descent and I
have like yellowish skin and so when I
shoot my videos I have to color correct
them in a way so that they have like
more of a pinkish hue to it so when I
look at my video footage from these
cameras it looks Pinker than normal but
it looks good to me and it's maybe
because of my skin tone I'm not entirely
sure but so I did a video with Lou from
unbox therapy Wow must forgot channel
name and on his set I look really yellow
like his skin looks normal but I look
like I'm from The Simpsons so I thought
maybe it's possible that who always
using this kind of color tint or color
grading on their video footage to make
Asian people look more natural I'm not
entirely sure but I actually looked at
this video footage and I'm okay with it
now video is not this camera strong
point it's definitely stills like it's
phenomenal for stills but just thrown
that theory out there Oh
fingerprint sensor I don't like the
optical fingerprint sensor on these
phones I prefer the ultrasonic on
Samsung's phones and actually prefer
capacitive sensors over any of these in
display sensors but I definitely prefer
the ultrasonic on the Samsung over the
optical on the p30s software-wise
I don't love emui it's been like this
every year there's just something about
the software that feels a little bit
glitchy a little bit unrefined it's
something that maybe people love but I
just use this thing for a few days and I
immediately remind myself of why I don't
love EMU i but you can always throw a
skin on this thing the speaker quality
on the p30 phones are also surprisingly
mediocre they sound very muffled I'm not
sure if it's on that they can fix with
software but both of these phones
I remember the p20 Pro from last year
had better sounding speakers in both
these that's just my memory of it these
sound quite muted and they also don't
have stereo speakers like the s10
devices have also if you're from the US
and you want to purchase this thing
overseas understand that there's
probably no warranty if you're from the
US because these things are not allowed
to be sold there now the reason why I
made this video
kind of to help people decide between
the two phones like if you're gonna get
a s10 or like one of the galaxy s 10 or
s10 a or s10 plus devices or one of
these new P 30 devices now on paper
these phones are like they're amazing
they're similarly priced but the huawei
phones because it has such an amazing
camera it would seem that this would be
the phone to get but there's something
about the galaxy phones this year that
just make them feel like a better phone
overall maybe I like the OLED punch out
on the screen better maybe I like the
software a little bit better it's a
little bit more refined than the emui
version that we're getting on the p30
phones I don't know they're great on
paper those cameras are crazy good but I
still have preference for the s10 so I
guess the takeaway here is if you're
interested in one of these phones either
the Samsung phones or the koala way
phones take a look at the feature that
you're drawn to and think is it
something I would use regularly
frequently or is it something that a
company is trying to sell me