In front of are arguably the best
13 inch Windows laptops on the market right now
This is the Huawei Matebook 13
this is the Matebook X pro
both kind of refreshed and brand new for 2019
Now
it's easy to kind of dismiss the brand
because some people said in the comments
to look at these devices and
they look like Macbook clones.
It's clearly look like they've been inspired by Apple's designs
and Huawei is a company that has a bit of a controversial past
they've been caught for
IP theft, and patent infringement,
they don't have the cleanest record at there.
However,
the fact remains these devices are very good.
If you're in the market for
some of that thin and light with great performance,
this should be on the short list.
So, i'm just gonna jump into performance real quick
These are running Whiskey Lake CPUs.
They're quad core, they're fast
and for anyone considering an ultrabook,
they'll get the job done.
But they're also running nVidia GPUs
and that's what makes these things special
cuz most ultrabooks that are thin and light like this
are usually running integrated graphics
These are running dedicated nVidia GPUs.
They're very similar in performance
despite having very different names
they're not gaming GPUs
but if you do wanna play some light games
they will work,
I'm still on the fence as value of these cards,
like, on one hand they're not super powerful,
of course, you can't do alot of graphically intensive stuff with it,
but, if you're looking for something that's thin and light
that does have graphical capabilities,
these are a perfect fit.
Now , I wanna talk about fans and thermals for a sec,
these have upgraded fans.
the 2018 models for both these devices had
kinda weak thermal performance,
they had loud fans, they had inappropriately sized fans,
these are better but hey're still not perfect.
The Matebook 13 are now running two fans,
instead of one,
but the Matebook X pro's still running one fan,
it's an improved fan, it's better
but, both of these devices
still run pretty loud on load
and when they're idling,
I feel like the fans come on more often
then I'd liked them to
maybe that's something can be fixed with software and
Huawei does put out software updates prettry frequently for their deivces
but
I just feel like these things should be quieter
than they're in their current state.
Now, the main difference between these two devices
is their displays.
this is running a 13 inch 1440p panel,
the X pro's higher res' 3K by 2K
and it's larger 14 inch panel
but the display on the Matebook X pro is
significantly brighter
I think for most people
they're going to be really drawn to this screen's brightness
and colors.
The Matebook 13's screen is already great,
it's just that the Matebook X pro's that much better.
In fact, if you're deciding between the two,
I really feel like you should just
figure out what type of screen you want
or need,
and then make your decision based on that
because it really is the fundamental difference
between the two.
the Matebook 13 ha a standard webcam up top,
but the X pro has the popup webcam
if you haven't seen this in the past,
they have a key that you can press
and the webcam pops up,
it's pretty cool, I don't think
it's a particularly great location like
when using it you can see your hands as you're typing,
but i think for most people
who don't use their webcams frequently,
this is a great lil' addition
like a kinda hidden webcam
that doesn't get in your way
and, the screen has a very thin bezel because of it.
the port selection is
relatively light on both these devices,
the Matebook 13 has two USB c
now there's a side supporting thunderbolt 3
and the left side can be used for charging
so they're port-light device for sure,
the X pro has an extra USB A
and 2 USB c ports support 4 lane thunderbolt 3.
the speakers on both of these laptops are very good.
the Matebook 13 has located at the bottom
but despite their not great location they sound really clean
the speakers on the X pro are definitely better.
There's two on the bottom
and there's two on the top
and they sound excellent.
they're seriously some of the best speakers
in the ultrabook market.
I will say they're comparable to Macbook's speakers which are
I'd say class-leading
These are on par with that.
AH, okay.
Keyboards.
These keyboards have obviously been inspired by
Macbook keyboards from the past.
and that's honestly a good thing
These are easy to get used to,
it's got a good layout,
easy to type on,
I think most people use these keyboards and
find them comfortable to use fright away.
At the top of the keyboard is a fingerprint sensor
Both of these devices lets you
login to the device with Windows Hello.
and oh, on the Matebook X pro,
there is something called Huawei Connect,
I don't have the ability to use it because
I don't have a Huawei phone that supports it,
but if you have one, you can place that phone
on the NFC sticker and it will transfer data from the phone.
and you're device which is pretty cool
Truthfully, I think it's a really cool and quite innovative
like if this is was an Apple feature
like people will go crazy for it,
it's just that Huawei phones that support that feature
aren't wide spread enough
to make this thing like super cool but i do think
it's a cool idea.
Um, oh trackpad.
their running Windows precision driver
you have good tracking, good gesture detection,
and the button mechanics on both of them are nice clean clicked
There does seem to be a little of a
quality control issue
I think both of these devices have a lil' bit of
play on the trackpad which
i wished wasn't there
but they exist
Also other things that I'm not super fond of
the Matebook 13 only supports 8 gigs of ram
and it probably won't affect most people
I think taht 8 gigs are sufficient for lot of work flows
but you can't upgrade it to 16,
the  Matebook X pro and also the
14 inch version of this supports 16
but this only supports 8.
The hardware on these Matebooks is excellent.
there's no denying that
but the pricing is a lil' bit more than
what i thought would be.
this comes at $1,300,
this comes in at $1,900.
and that's both for the dedicated graphics versions
that's on par with any of the premium
Windows laptops on the mark right now
there is nothing wrong with that,
like these are clearly premium devices but
last year, this one in particular
the Matebook X pro was
it was like 20% cheaper than now
and I think it's gone to the point where
Huawei knows that their making good hardware
they know they have one the best laptops on the market
so they bumped up the price because they can
the X pro costs more than the Razor Blade Stealth
and that was already a very expensive device
The Matebook lineup has great build quality
the X pro does have slightly better
build quality it's a unibody design
so the panels are just a lil' tighter
but they're both well built.
Regards on people calling these clones of Apple's Macbooks
I can kinda understand where they're coming from
they obviously inspired this design
fomr Apple's Macbook lineup,
and even the color of the devices
like the grey unit they call it space grey
they could have called it anything
they could've called it meteor grey,
rock grey,
storm grey but they went with space grey because
that's what Apple did
and that's what Huawei rolls,
But these devices are excellent
like they're just such good hardware that
You know, I didn't make this video to be like
hey, everyone should buy these devices.
I'm certainly not saying that
but if you're in the market for
a thin and light ultrabook,
that has performance like this,
you should definitely look at them.
Because they're that good.